@ codes.mariam@gmail.com

www.mariam.codes

github.com/mavima

in linkedin.com/maria-vihla-manninen

### MARIA MANNINEN

WEB DEVELOPER

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Originally a journalist, I have also worked in administration in international environment. A couple of years ago I decided to learn to code and found my new career. At the moment I am working on my own application and other websites, while always keeping on learning.

#### TOP SKILLS

- Ruby & Ruby on Rails
- HTML / CSS
- JavaScript & React
- jQuery
- SQL
- PHP
- WordPress
- Photoshop
- Project management

# PERSONAL WEB PROJECT

www.famtravel.eu
Famtravel is a community
for travelling families
sharing tips – meant to
make it easier to visit other
cities also with children.



#### **EXPERIENCE**

Since September 2019:

#### Freelance web developer

- Creating websites for clients using Wordpress as CMS
- Developing applications for personal projects

9/2015 - 4/2019: Nordea Investment Funds S.A.

#### **Business Support Officer**

- Event organization and assistance of the management
- Expense follow-up and reporting.

5/2013 – 8/2015: Embassy of Finland in Luxembourg

Assistant of the ambassador

11/2012 - 5/2013: Rovi Corporation S.A.

Schedule editor

2003 – 2007: several medias in Finland News reporter, editor and news reader

#### **EDUCATION**

September 2019 – present: online courses Several online courses to learn e.g. PHP, WordPress, React, Scrum & Agile, SEO etc..

July - August 2019: Le Wagon Barcelona

#### Full Stack Ruby on Rails Bootcamp

9 weeks intensive coding bootcamp learning to use Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS / SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, MVC Architecture and GitHub.

1998 – 2003: University of Turku, Finland **Master of Arts** (literature, communications, languages)

#### LANGUAGE COMPETENCES

English Full working proficiency \*\*\*\*

Finnish Native \*\*\*\*

French Working proficiency \*\*\*

Spanish Working proficiency \*\*\*

German Limited working proficiency \*\*\*

Limited proficiency \*\*\*

### **INTERESTS**

Coding and design, languages, hiking, gardening, reading